So I'm taking a moment now to explain that the training costs of optimizing a model for this course
이 코스를 위한 모델을 최적화하는 데 드는 훈련 비용은 아주 적다는 걸 말씀드리고
can be very slim indeed.
싶군요
It can be a matter of a couple of cents, and you don't need to go berserk and be doing what I'm doing
몇 센트만 있으면 되니까 저처럼 미친 듯이 A100
and using A100 boxes and, and big training runs.
상자를 들고 훈련할 필요 없어요
And just to to clarify that.
확실히 해두죠
So first of all, as I explained last time, you can run on a box like a T4, which is very cheap.
먼저, 지난번에 설명했듯이 T4 같은 박스에서 작동할 수 있어요 아주 저렴하죠
You can have a batch size that the largest that will fit on that box.
상자에 들어가는 가장 큰 배치 사이즈를 가질 수 있어요
It's probably 1 or 2, um, and then run training that way.
한두 번 연습하고 그렇게 달리기를 해요
But if you do that, actually with the training data set that we've been working with, it will take
하지만 그렇게 하면 우리가 작업해온 트레이닝 데이터 집합으로
a long time, which is still going to add up to a bit because we've just got lots of data.
시간이 오래 걸릴 겁니다 비트가 많아도 시간이 좀 더 걸리겠죠
And I wanted to explain that actually, it's not necessary to be training against this monstrous data
이 괴물 같은 데이터에 맞서 훈련할 필요는 없다는 걸 설명하고 싶었어요
set.
이렇게 하는 이유는 여러분께 좋은, 꽤 강력한 결과를 보여드리고 싶어서죠 하지만 훨씬
you'll get great results with a much smaller data set too.
적은 데이터 집합으로도 훌륭한 결과를 얻을 수 있어요
Now, one thing I would suggest though one you can just take the data set of 400,000 data points and
제가 제안하고 싶은 것은 데이터 포인트 400,000개의 데이터 집합 중에서
just select from it the first 20,000 and run with that sub data set, and that would be totally fine.
첫 20,000개를 선택해서 하위 데이터 집합으로 실행해도 된다는 거예요
Um, it's probably better if you're going to do that.
그렇게 하는 게 좋겠어요
If instead you focus in on one particular type of product that's being priced, because that way the
가격이 매겨지는 특정 제품에 집중하는 대신에요 그래야 모델이 해당 제품에
model will have opportunity to learn all about that product.
관해 전부 배울 기회가 생기니까요
Um, for example, you could choose appliances, which was one of the data sets that we pulled down
예를 들어 어플라이언스를 선택할 수 있는데 처음에 H깅페이스 허브에서 뽑아낸
from the Huggingface hub at the very beginning.
데이터 세트 중 하나였죠
Um, and instead of bringing down all of these data sets, you could simply bring down appliances only.
이 모든 데이터 세트를 없애는 대신 가전제품만 없애는 거죠
And I've set up a, um, a Jupyter notebook.
주피터 공책을 준비했어요
Uh, not not on Colab, just just a local notebook.
콜랍은 아니고 동네 공책이에요
It's in week six, where the other, uh, days were for week six.
6주 차예요, 다른 날은 6주 차까지 갔거든요
We actually built this data set the full one on day two.
둘째 날 전체 데이터를 구축했어요
So this is a copy of day two, but it just made much simpler and more narrow to only look at appliances.
이건 둘째 날 복사본인데 훨씬 간단하고 가전제품만 볼 수 있게 편리하게 만들었어요
And because it's such a small data set, it will run super fast.
데이터 집합이 작아서 아주 빨리 실행될 거예요
We connect it to the environment.
환경과 연결하는 거죠
This is will be a throwback to the to the past.
과거를 떠올리게 하는 요리예요
It's complaining because I've already logged in to Huggingface and I tried to log in a second time,
이미 허깅페이스에 로그인해서 불평하는 거예요 두 번째도 로그인하려고
but ignore that.
했는데 무시하세요
Um, and now we're just going to take, uh, the data set names, and I've commented everything out
이제 데이터 세트 이름을 입력할게요 어플라이언스만 빼고 전부 주석을 달았어요 기억하실지
except for appliances, which you may remember, was one of the really small data sets.
모르겠지만 아주 작은 데이터 세트였죠
Um, uh, Hugging Face is really upset with me for, uh, running it multiple times, but there we go.
포옹하는 얼굴이 정말 속상해요 여러 번 실행했거든요
Off it runs.
출발했어요
The total time it takes to load in this data set is, uh, about a 0.2 of a minute, if I remember right.
이 데이터 세트를 로드하는 데 걸리는 총 시간은 0분 정도 제 기억이 맞는다면 2분 정도
Uh, 0.3 of a minute even, uh, and when we do that, we've got 28,000 items.
0살요 3분 만에 끝내면 28,000개가 완성되죠
Um, so it's a lot smaller than the 400,000 data set we've been working with.
우리가 작업한 400,000개의 데이터 세트보다 훨씬 작아요
But it's a perfectly respectable number for Flora, and it has the benefit of being focused on appliances.
하지만 플로라에게는 아주 괜찮은 수치였고 가전제품에 집중할 수 있어서 유리했어요
So it's a narrower data set.
데이터 집합이 더 좁아지죠
Um, and, uh, yeah, I, um, you can follow the rest of these charts.
어, 그리고 이 차트들 따라가시면 돼요 REST
I've taken out the charts that don't matter.
안 중요한 차트는 뺐어요
Like the comparison of different data types.
서로 다른 데이터 타입의 비교 같은 거요
This is the price.
이게 그 대가예요
The average is.
평균은 그렇죠
It's a smaller average.
평균보다 낮아요
Um, but still you get all the way up to 999.
999까지 갈 수 있어요. Get it.
And that is the, the, the curve.
이게 바로 곡선이에요
Um, and then to curate this, there's nothing really to it.
그리고 이걸 정리하는 건 사실 별거 없어요
We're going to take the entire data set.
전체 데이터 세트를 가져오는 거죠
This is that same chart now for our smaller data set showing that there isn't a material correlation
작은 데이터 집합에 대한 같은 도표입니다 물질적 상관관계가 없다는 걸 보여주죠
Um, and we can just quickly confirm that the same thing applies to the tokens as we checked before.
음, 아까 확인했던 것과 같은 것이 토큰에 적용된다는 것을 빠르게 확인해 볼게요.
Um, and then finally when we divide that into a training and test data set, we'll take the 25,000
마지막으로 트레이닝과 테스트 데이터로 나눌 때 트레이닝용 아이템 25,000개
items for training and then 2000 for test.
테스트용 2000개를 가져가요
Um, and everything else will work just great here.
다른 건 다 잘 될 거예요
Uh, you'll see the training prompt.
훈련 시간을 표시해 뒀어요
The test prompt.
테스트 프롬프트요
We can plot the distribution of prices in the test set.
테스트 세트에서 가격 배분을 계산할 수 있어요
There we go.
됐어요
We've got a perfectly decent spread.
완벽한 스프레드가 있어요
And then finally we can create the prompts from this, just as we did before, and then upload this
마지막으로 아까 했던 것처럼 프롬프트만 생성하면 됩니다 그리고 이걸he깅face에 업로드 합니다
to Huggingface, potentially give it a different name like I've called it light data here.
다른 이름을 붙일 수도 있죠 라이트 데이터라고 부를 수 있어요
Um, and also make the two pickle files, uh, and yeah, then you can use that in your training instead.
피클 파일 두 개를 만들 수 있어요 그걸 훈련에 활용할 수 있죠
It will build a model based on smaller populations of data that will be focused on predicting the prices
적은 데이터량을 바탕으로 모델을 만들 겁니다 다양한 가전제품의 가격을 예측하는 데 집중할
of just home appliances, rather than all the different types.
겁니다 다른 종류가 아니라요
This will work great.
이거면 될 거예요
I think it'll be a good exercise for you to have to make those small changes in various places in the
코드의 다양한 곳에 작은 변화를 주는 것이 좋은 운동이 될 겁니다
code to focus in on this smaller data set.
작은 데이터 집합에 집중하기 위해서요
Uh, and I have run this myself, and I can confirm that whatever result we're going to discover, uh,
제가 직접 실행해 봤는데 어떤 결과가 나오든 확인시켜 줄 수 있어요 400,000로
from the main run we're doing with the 400,000, the same will apply in this case in terms of how it
했던 메인 실행에서도요 이 경우에도 같은 결과가 적용됩니다 다른 모델에 비해 어떻게 차곡차곡
stacks up compared to other models.
쌓이느냐에 있어서요
Not as much as will be the case with the the bigger data set, but uh, without giving the game away
데이터가 많을수록 더 잘 알 수 있겠지만 게임에서 중요한 일이 벌어질 거라는 걸 미리
that the the important things will happen even if you're focused on appliances.
알려주지 않으면 되죠 가전제품에 집중하더라도요
And obviously when you're dealing with the data set at 25,000, uh, you can, uh, get through it very
25,000에 데이터셋을 다룰 때는 아주 빠르게 get을
quickly indeed.
할 수 있죠
Um, but should you do that and should you then get the bug like I have and want to then go and do a
하지만 그렇게 하고 저처럼 버그를 확보해서 더 크게 달리길 원하나요?
Then of course, you can add in more types and you can spend a few dollars and then be doing it for
물론 더 많은 유형을 추가해 몇 달러 더 써서 전체 데이터 세트를
the full data set.
만들 수도 있죠
Anyway, I thought I'd go through that.
어쨌든, 그 과정을 거쳐야겠다고 생각했죠
This.
이거요
This may be a good revision for people on how we curated the data and should you wish, a smaller data
데이터 큐레이팅에 있어 좋은 수정안이 될 수 있습니다 더 작은 데이터 집합을 원하신다면요
set.
어떻게 하는지 알려주죠
All right.
좋아요
In the next video, we go to weights and biases, and we look at how the big run with the 400,000 is
다음 영상에서는 무게와 편향성을 살펴보고 400,000도 회전을 어떻게 진행하는지
coming along.
살펴보죠
And we poke around weights and biases to see what more can be done there.
무게와 편향성을 따져보고 뭘 더 할 수 있는지 보죠
See you there.
거기서 봐요